二零二四年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试，上海英语试卷六月听力部分，现在开始。
Listening comprehension,
Section A. Directions.
In Section A, you will hear ten short conversations between two speakers.
At the end of each conversation, a question will be asked about what was said.
The conversations and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a conversation and a question about it, read the four possible
answers on your paper and decide which one is the best answer to the question you
have heard. 1.
Have you decided where to go during your holiday?
I'll first fly to Beijing and then to Shenyang by train.
After that, I'll rent a and drive to Dalian.
2. will the man go from Shenyang to Dalian?
2. So, you didn't get lost in Hangzhou?
I did actually, but I met some friendly people.
They showed me the
3. can be learned from the conversation?
3. Mr. Smith seems like a tough guy.
Actually, he's the nicest person in the office and full of ideas.
4. What happened to you yesterday?
The professor waited long in his office.
It was my fault.
I fell over on the way to school and broke my phone, so I couldn't call him.
5. can be learned about the man?
5. The room looks perfect with the new furniture.
What else shall we do?
We need to the wall repainted and call the repairman for the air conditioner.
6. are the speakers mainly talking about?
6. This has been an unusually cold autumn.
Can you imagine I'm even wearing a wool sweater?
7. can be learned about the woman?
Hey, I've got a ticket for tomorrow's volleyball championship.
That should be more exciting than watching it on TV, especially with so many famous
players there. 8.
will the man most probably go tomorrow?
8. Yesterday I had some delicious noodles in a lovely restaurant on Nanjing Road.
I'd like to have a try tomorrow.
What's the name of the restaurant?
Question. What does the man mean?
9. So you taught Chinese in Africa for three months.
How did you like your experience there?
Once there, I was drawn to its unique culture.
I felt three months was rather short for me.
Question. What does the woman imply?
10. You won the speech contest!
You are the pride of our class.
Thank you. I owe it to my team.
Without their commitment, I wouldn't have made it so far.
According to the woman, what contributed to her success in the contest?
Section B Directions In Section B, you will hear two passages and one longer
conversation. After each passage or conversation, you will be asked several
questions. The passages and the conversation will be read twice, but the questions
will be spoken only once.
When you hear a question, read the four possible answers on your paper and decide
which one is the best answer to the question you have heard.
Questions 11 through 13 are based on the following passage.
Popcorn is a popular snack, but its origin dates back thousands of years.
Back then, in North America, native people first discovered corn burst open when
heated. In 1519, when the Spanish army conquered some parts of North America,
a soldier first saw popcorn when he met the native people.
Popcorn was important to the natives as food and as decorations for their
headdresses on great occasions.
Around 1612, French explorers around the Great Lakes in America met native people
who used heated sand to make popcorn.
Story has it that a native man brought a bag of to celebrate the big harvest in
1621. In America, popcorn gained popularity at fairs starting from the late 19th due
to its affordability and ease of consumption on the go.
The mass production and commercialization of popcorn began during the early 20th
century with the invention of the device designed specifically for making this
snack. However, popcorn didn't become popular among moviegoers until the mid -20th
century. Today, it is enjoyed worldwide both in its traditional form and with
various flavors. Now listen again.
Popcorn is a popular snack, but its origin dates back thousands of years.
Back then, in North America, native people first discovered corn burst open when
heated. In 1519, when the Spanish army conquered some parts of North America, a
soldier first saw popcorn when he met the native people.
Popcorn was important to the natives as food and as decorations for their
headdresses on great occasions.
Around 1612, French explorers around the Great Lakes in America met native people
who used heated sand to make popcorn.
Story has it that a native man brought a bag of to celebrate the big harvest in
1621. In America, popcorn gained popularity at fairs starting from the late 19th due
to its affordability and ease of consumption on go.
The mass production and commercialization of popcorn began during the early 20th
century with the invention of the device designed specifically for making this
snack. However, popcorn didn't become popular among moviegoers until the mid -20th
century. Today, it is enjoyed worldwide both in its traditional form and with
various flavors. Questions 11.
What is the passage mainly about?
12. According to the passage, what led to the mass production and commercialization
of popcorn? 13.
When did popcorn become a popular snack in movie theaters?
Questions 14 through 16 are based on the following passage.
In today's class, I'll introduce the scientific method.
is a process used by scientists to explore the natural world and acquire new
knowledge. It follows five steps, observing, proposing an explanation,
experimenting, analyzing, and making conclusions.
First, a scientist observes interesting things in the world.
For example, he might notice that plants grow bigger when watered
Based on his observations, he then comes up with a possible explanation that needs
to be proved.
In our example, the scientist assumes that watering plants daily helps them grow
larger. After that, he designs and carries out experiments to test this explanation.
He might set up an experiment where some plants are watered daily while others are
not, to see if there's a difference in growth between the two groups.
After collecting data from his experiments, the scientist analyzes it to determine
whether his explanation is supported.
In our example, the growth of both groups of plants would be measured and compared.
Finally, the scientist draws a conclusion about what he has learned.
If his explanation was correct, he might adjust it to be more specific or test it
further. If it was incorrect, a new explanation would be needed for his
observations. So if the watered plants didn't grow larger, he would need to consider
alternative explanations and test them instead.
Now listen again.
In today's class, I'll introduce the scientific method.
It is a process used by scientists to explore the natural world and acquire new
knowledge. follows five steps.
Observing, proposing an explanation, experimenting,
analyzing, and making conclusions.
First, a scientist observes interesting things in the wild.
For example, he might notice that plants grow bigger when watered Based on his
observations, he then comes up with a possible explanation that needs to be proved.
In our example, the scientist assumes that watering plants daily helps them grow
larger. After that, he designs and carries out experiments to test this explanation.
He might set up an experiment where some plants are watered daily while others are
not, to see if there's a difference in growth between the two groups.
After collecting data from his experiments,
the scientist analyzes it to determine whether his explanation is supported.
In our example, the growth of both groups of plants would be measured and compared.
Finally, the scientist draws a conclusion about what he has learned.
If his explanation was correct, he might adjust it to be more specific or test it
further. If it was incorrect, a new explanation would be needed for his
observations. So, if the watered didn't grow larger, he would need to consider
alternative explanations and test them instead.
Questions 14. What is the passage mainly about?
15. to the passage, what is the next step after a comes up with an explanation for
his observations? 16.
If watering plants didn't make them grow larger, what would the scientist need to
do? 17 -20.
17 through 20 are based on the following conversation.
Excuse me, does any bus go from the main campus to Sunshine Square?
Sure. Nice. When does it run?
The first bus leaves the main campus at 6am and the last one 6pm.
Wait, I think the schedule changed not long ago.
Yes, now it till 8pm at night.
Okay. Does it come at regular intervals?
It runs every 2 hours.
Is it the same on weekends?
No, it runs from 7pm to 7pm and on a less frequent schedule, every 3 hours.
I see. What are the pick -up points?
The library, the health clinic,
the community centre and the Happy Supermarket.
The Happy Supermarket is next to my apartment block.
By the way, can I take my bike on the bus?
I'm not sure.
Maybe you could ask the driver, or you might just ride your bike to the subway
station and take the train instead.
Right. Thanks for all your help.
My pleasure. Now listen again.
Excuse me, any bus go from the main campus to Sunshine Square?
Sure. Nice. When does it run?
The first bus leaves the main campus at 6am and the last one 6pm.
Wait, I think the schedule changed not long ago.
Yes, now it runs till 8pm at night.
Okay. Does it come at regular intervals?
It runs every 2 hours.
Is it the same on weekends?
No, it runs from 7pm to 7pm and on a less frequent schedule, every 3 hours.
I see. What are the pick -up points?
The library, the health clinic,
the community centre and the Happy Supermarket.
Great. The Happy Supermarket is next to my apartment block.
By the way, can I take my bike on the bus?
I'm not sure.
Maybe you could ask the driver, or you might just ride your bike to the subway
station and take the train instead.
Right. Thanks for all your help.
My pleasure. Questions.
17. What are the speakers mainly talking about?
18. When does the last bus leave the main campus on Saturday?
19. Which pick -up point is closest to the woman's apartment block?
20. What does the man suggest the woman ask the driver about?
That's the end of listening comprehension.
听力部分到此结束。嗯。